Register of the Poland. Poselstwo (Bulgaria) Miscellaneous Records
Hoover Institution Archives
Poland. Poselstwo (Bulgaria) miscellaneous records,
1919-1931
45012
Poland. Poselstwo (Bulgaria)
1 manuscript box (0.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, memoranda, and telegrams, relating to Legation operations and diplomatic relations between Poland and Bulgaria.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1945
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternative Form Available
Also available on microfilm (2 reels).
Historical Note
Polish Legation in Bulgaria.
Scope and Content Note
The records of the Polish Legation in Bulgaria (Poselstwo Rzeczposplitej Polskiej w Sofii) were received by the Hoover Institution in 1945 and consist mainly of telegrams exchanged with the Foreign Ministry Headquarters in Warsaw, as well as with various Polish embassies. Also included are some letters, instructions, memoranda, and reports.
The materials relate to the operations of the legation and to diplomatic relations between Poland and Bulgaria, giving a fragmentary insight into the functioning of a Polish diplomatic post in the first decade of Poland's independence.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the repository's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Bulgaria.; Bulgaria--Foreign relations--Poland.; Poland.; Poland--Foreign relations--Bulgaria.; Poland. Ministerstwo Spraw Zagranicznych.
Series Description
- Telegrams, 1919-1931. (Box 1)
  Incoming and outgoing telegrams, arranged chronologically. Includes some letters, instructions, memoranda, and reports
Container List
- TELEGRAMS, 1919-1931. (Box 1)
  Incoming and outgoing telegrams, as well as some letters, instructions, memoranda, and reports
  - 1919
    - Incoming (Folder 1: 1)
    - Outgoing (Folder 1: 2)
  - 1920
    - Incoming (Folder 1: 3)
    - Outgoing (Folder 1: 4)
  - 1921
    - Incoming (Folder 1: 5)
    - Outgoing (Folder 1: 6)
  - 1922
    - Incoming (Folder 1: 7)
    - Outgoing (Folder 1: 8)
  - 1923
    - Incoming (Folder 1: 9)
    - Outgoing (Folder 1: 10)
  - 1924
    - Incoming (Folder 1: 11)
    - Outgoing (Folder 1: 12)
  - 1925
    - Incoming (Folder 1: 13)
    - Outgoing (Folder 1: 14)
  - 1926
    - Incoming (Folder 1: 15)
    - Outgoing (Folder 1: 16)
  - 1927
    - Incoming (Folder 1: 17)
    - Outgoing (Folder 1: 18)
  - 1928
    - Incoming (Folder 1: 19)
    - Outgoing (Folder 1: 20)
  - 1929
    - Incoming
      - General
        - General (Folder 1: 21)
        - Letters (Folder 1: 22)
      - Embassies (Folder 1: 23)
    - Outgoing
      - General (Folder 1: 24)
      - Embassies (Folder 1: 25)
  - 1930
    - Incoming
      - General
        - General (Folder 1: 26)
        - Letters (Folder 1: 27)
      - Embassies (Folder 1: 28)
    - Outgoing (Folder 1: 29)
  - 1931
    - Incoming
      - General
        - General (Folder 1: 30)
        - Letters (Folder 1: 31)
      - Embassies (Folder 1: 32)
    - Outgoing
      - General (Folder 1: 33)
      - Embassies (Folder 1: 34)